John Teckemeyer

Full Stack Web Developer

Brentwood, California (510) 673-8723 johnteckemeyer@gmail.com github.com/TheTeck linkedin.com/in/john-teckemeyer

SUMMARY

I first started programming in high school over twenty years ago. Though my college career took a turn for another passion of mine, music, I have never lost the joy I had for programming. Now I have decided to leave my comfortable job of seventeen years to finally pursue this passion of mine and had recently enrolled and graduated from a boot camp for full stack web development. I am excited and looking forward to being a part of a team of like-minded people and getting to use my skills to help build amazing technologies.

SKILLS

CSS <u>Javascript</u> <u>Python</u> <u>HTML</u> <u>Sass</u> React **NodeJS** <u>Django</u> **ExpressJS MongoDB PostgreSQL** <u>AWS S3</u> **MongoDB Atlas VSCode** Git/Github **OAuth** JWT Auth

PROJECTS

EduSpark

An online space for teachers and parents to communicate about students and their progress in class

- Effectively communicated with UX team and translated their vision into a usable application
- Wrote Class model schema and entire pipeline for its CRUD operations
- As per the design from the UX team, I developed the dashboard for the teachers on the frontend

Sheet Music Maker

An online sheet music editor with a social networking aspects that allows users to share their work and view other uses' works as well

- Frontend developed using React, Javascript, CSS and Semantic UI
- Backend developed with Node, Express and MongoDB/Mongoose
- Provided user security through JWT authentication
- Created a sheet music editor GUI using only React and CSS

Our Alley

An online networking app that allows users to create playdates for their dogs. Using the Google Maps API, users can locate nearby dogs that are in the database

- Backend developed with Python, Django and a PostgreSQL database
- As scrum master, I defined and organized the particular tasks needed for our team to achieve our goals and effectively distributed duties.
- A major focus of mine in this project was to implement the functionality to geocode locations to locate other users within a certain radius of the current user using Google Maps API.

EXPERIENCE

Teckemeyer Luthiery, Brentwood, CA – *Owner/Luthier*

September 2017 - Present

Handcrafted high-quality classical guitars for clients. This being a one man business, I handled every aspect of running a business on top of developing my craft to significantly improve my product on each iteration.

Trader Joe's, Brentwood, CA – *Section Leader*

April 2004 – January 2021

Managed multiple departments and provided superior customer service.

EDUCATION

General Assembly, Remote – *Software Engineering*

February 2021 - May 2021

12-week training program, full-time, 500+ hours, project-based program taught by industry leaders.

CSU East Bay, Hayward, CA – Music Composition

September 2002 – June 2008

Music theory, orchestration and multiple musical instrument performance taught by world-renowned musicians.